A Finding Aid to the Solon H. Borglum and Borglum Family Papers, 1864-2002, in the Archives of American Art AAA.borgsolo
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, 1864-1986; Series 8; (Box 9-13, MGP 1, MGP 3, OV 15-16; 2.0 linear feet)
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1895-1967, undated; 8.2; (Not scanned)
    - Portrait Busts, 1905, 1923, undated; (See also Box 11, F19) (Box OV 15)
    - Miscellaneous Sculptures, undated; (See also Box 11, F21) (Box OV 16)
  - Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, undated; 8.3; (Not scanned)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, General John B. Gordon Memorial, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 3)
      (4 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1)
    - Glass Plate Negative of Portrait Bust, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 4)
      (1 glass plate negative housed in MGP 3)
    - Negatives, Monica Borglum Davies, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 5)
    - Negative of Unidentified People, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 6)
    - Negatives of Artwork, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 7)
    - Slides, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 8)
    - Transparencies of Solon Borglum Paintings, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 9)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 4 Glass negatives (Box MGP 1)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 1 Glass negatives (Box MGP 3)
- Artwork, 1890-1921, undated; Series 9; (Box 12-13; 0.3 linear feet)
  Artwork contains many sketches by Solon Borglum, such as figure sketches for some of his sculptural works and for his book Sound Construction, as well as sketches he made on tracing paper, mostly of architectural design elements. This series also contains Emma Borglum's drawings of jewelry designs and sketches by Gutzon Borglum, including a sketch of Solon, possibly drawn while they were working together in 1894. Also found are original etchings for Silvermine Group of Artists Exhibition Announcements, a large illuminated poem made for Solon and Emma at the time of their marriage by writer William Theodore Peters, a military cartoon, and other artwork by unidentified artists. The folder of miscellaneous artwork by others includes etchings by artists Robert Fulton Logan and Frank Sohn.
  - Solon Borglum, Figure Sketches, undated; (See also Box 13, F16) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 10)
  - Solon Borglum, Tracing Paper Sketches, undated; (See also Box 13, F17) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 11)
  - Solon Borglum, Miscellaneous Sketches, 1890-1891, 1919, 1921, undated; (3 folders; see also Box 13, F18) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 12-14)
  - Emma Borglum, Jewelry Designs, 1901, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 15)
  - Gutzon Borglum, Sketches, 1894, 1900, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 16)
  - William Theodore Peters, "The Betrothal", 1898; (See Box 13, F19) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 17)
  - Silvermine Group of Artists, Etchings for Exhibition Announcements, 1913, undated (Box 12 (pam), Folder 18)
  - Unidentified Artist, Military Cartoon, circa 1918; (See Box 13, F20; not scanned) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Artwork by Others, 1919, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 20-21)
  - Miscellaneous Artwork by Others, unidentified, 1919, undated; (Not scanned) (Box 12 (pam), Folder 22)
  - Solon Borglum, Figure Sketches, undated; (See also Box 12, F10) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 16)
  - Solon Borglum, Tracing Paper Sketches, undated; (See also Box 12, F11) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 17)
  - Solon Borglum, Miscellaneous Sketches, 1890-1891, 1919, 1921, undated; (See also Box 12, F12-14) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 18)
  - William Theodore Peters, "The Betrothal", 1898; (See Box 12, F17) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Artist, Military Cartoon, circa 1918; (See Box 12, F19; not scanned) (Box 13 (sol), Folder 20)